A Guide to the Secretary of Public Safety Records, 1998-2001
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Secretary of Public Safety Records, 1998-2001
Library of Virginia
38945
15 cu. ft.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Privacy protected information closed for 100 years after date record created. Types of records restricted include, but are not limited to: Prisoner medical records, juvenile criminal records, Commonwealth of Virginia employment applications, job interview notes, employee performance reviews, and employee grievance materials that were sent to the Secretary of Public Safety and are part of the constituent correspondence series. Privacy protected material has been sealed but has not been removed from the collection.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from the Office of the Secretary of Public Safety by Kevin Massengill and D.M. Taylor, 11 January 2002.
Biographical/Historical Information
In 1970, the Governor's Management Commission Study recommended the creation of six "Deputy Governors" to assist the Chief Executive in his managerial duties. Compatible functions of government were grouped under these administrative heads, who would serve as the Governors top management team or "secretariats," as they were called now. Governor Linwood Holton's top priority for the 1972 session of the General Assembly was a proposal for a Governor's Cabinet, reorganizing state agencies into six major departments--each headed by a secretary appointed by the governor.
Transportation and public safety was one of these six departments. The office of Secretary of Transportation and Public Safety was created on April 8, 1972, by an act passed by the General Assembly. Governor Holton appointed Wayne A. Whitham, a member of the Winchester City Council, as the first Secretary of Transportation and Public Safety.
When Whitman took office on July 1, 1972, he was responsible for the State Highway Commission, Division of Motor Vehicles, Department of State Police, Highway Safety Division, Office of Emergency Services, Department of Military Affairs, Virginia State Crime Commission, and the Law Enforcement Officers Training Standards Commission.
The Office has undergone a series of administrative reorganizations since 1972. On April 12, 1976, the Legislature established separate secretariats for transportation and for public safety, effective July 1, 1976. On July 1, 1984, the offices were again compined. Most recently, the Secretary of Transporation and Public Safety was divided into seperate secretariats on February 22, 1990. The Secretary of Public Safety is a member of the Governor's Cabinet, and is appointed by the governor, subject to confirmation by the General Assembly.
Currently the Secretary of Public Safety is responsible for the direction or jurisdiction over the following state agencies and boards: Commonwealth's Attorneys' Services Board, Department of Alcoholic Beverage Control, Department of Correctional Education, Department of Corrections, Department of Criminal Justice Services, Department of Emergency Services, Virginia Department of Fire Programs, Department of Juvenile Justice, Department of Military Affairs, Virginia Parole Board, and the Department of State Police.
In December 1997 Governor-elect James S. Gilmore III named Gary K. Aronhalt as Secretary of Public Safety. Aronhalt was Gilmore's chief assistant when Gilmore was Henrico County Commonwealth's Attorney and Virginia Attorney General. Aronhalt served until the end of the Gilmore administration in January 2002.
Scope and Content Information
The records of the Secretary of Public Safety consist of constituent correspondence to the Governro referred to the secretary for response and correspondence arranged by department and subject files. Constituent correspondence are arranged by tracking numbers assigned by the Governor's office and date received. Subjects included are law enforcement issues, Virginia State Police, ABC stores, gun control, capital punishment, drunk driving, parole, Virginia National Guard, pay raises for law enforcement officers, 9/11 terrorist attacks, and Virginia's juvenile detention system. A significant number of correspondence consist of letters from family and friends of Virginia prison inmates appealing to the Governor to intervene in their case. Gary K. Aronhalt, Secretary of Public Safety, wrote responses to nearly all of these letters.
Additional correspondence are arranged by department, by date and subject. Notable documents filed with each department include memos from Aronhalt to each agency head, dated May 1999, reviewing each department's strategic plan. Correspondence filed under the Department of Military Affairs and chronologically (see 14 December 2000) describe the racial discrimination complaints made by African-American members of the Virginia National Guard.
Notable topics include terrorism, COPS (Community Oriented Policing Services), New Partnership Commission, SABRE Project (Substance Abuse Reduction Effort), and Virginia Exile. Notable documents concerning terrorism include: a memo from Gary K. Aronhalt to Mark Miner, Press Secretary to Governor Gilmore, dated 15 June 2000, recommending a fifteen point strategy on ways to increase Gilmore's national exposure and name-association with terrorism preparedness policy; summary of the 28 September 2001 meeting of the Virginia Preparedness and Security Panel and the Panel's report to the Governor, dated 30 November 2001. Notable documents concerning Virginia Exile include: bi-weekly reports on the status of Virginia Exile written by Mike Costigan of the Virginia Department of Criminal Justice Services to Aronhalt between August 1999 and August 2000 and Project Exile grant applications for Fiscal Year 2000 for Halifax County, Chesapeake, Lynchburg, Petersburg, Richmond, and Roanoke.
Contents List
- Constituent Correspondence - 1998
  - Correspondence Numbers 197-1013 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence Numbers 1024-1750 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence Numbers 1763-3659 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence Numbers 3668-3766 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence Numbers 3769-11018 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence Numbers 11019-13787 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence Numbers 13790-16423 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence Numbers 16636-17366 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence Numbers 17380-18263 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence Numbers 18279-20723 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence Numbers 20727-21140 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence Numbers 21230-22068 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence Numbers 22091-24561 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence Numbers 24562-25362 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence Numbers 25373-25996 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence Numbers 26474-27079 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence Numbers 27122-27411 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence Numbers 27445-27922 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence Numbers 27924-28205 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Constituent Correspondence - 1998
  - Correspondence Numbers 28212-28786 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence Numbers 28790-29433 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence Number 29451 (petition) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence Numbers 29456-29885 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence Numbers 29901-30346 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence Numbers 30350-30853 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence Numbers 30864-31342 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence Numbers 31351-31751 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence Numbers 31778-31949 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence Numbers 31960-32264 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence Numbers 32271-32651 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence Numbers 32697-33206 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence Numbers 33209-34045 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence Numbers 34141-34467 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence Numbers 34478-34893 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence Numbers 34894-35380 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence Numbers 35384-35552 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence Numbers 35563-35624 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence Numbers 35642-35853 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence Numbers 35866-36070 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence Numbers 36072-36211 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Constituent Correspondence- 1998-1999
  - Correspondence Numbers, 36213-36306 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 36359-36743 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 36748-37274 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 37278-37998 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 38040 (3 folders, sealed, privacy protected)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 38062-38519 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence Numbers,38527-49443 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 49452-50127 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 50128-50598 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 50607-51591 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 51613-52703 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 52719-53668 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 53725-54921 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 54923 (part 1 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 54923 (part 2 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 54970-55557 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 55606-56484 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 56518-57734 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 57736-58678 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Constituent Correspondence- 1999
  - Correspondence Numbers, 58812-59644 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 59687-60728 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 60729 (2 folders, sealed, privacy protected)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 60732-61804 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 61837-62367 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 62453-63249 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 63261-64866 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 64961-64866 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 65886-67018 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 67086-67271 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 67315-67573 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 67623-68190 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 68192-68355 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 68356-68552 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 68576-69192 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 69098-69477 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 69499-69997 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 70007-70551 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 70587-71304 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 71315 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 71329-71960 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Constituent Correspondence- 1999
  - Correspondence Numbers, 71992-72363 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence Number, 72697 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 72370-73546 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 73595-75135 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 75485-77021 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 77035-77817 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 77818-78111 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 78150-78758 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 75759-79780 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 79798-79897 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 79918-80368 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 80406-81014 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 81051-81510 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 81543-81921 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 81931-82701 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 82703-83687 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 83689-84641 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 84747-85591 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 85597-86173 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 86199-86799 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Constituent Correspondence- 1999
  - Correspondence Numbers, 86816-87809 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 88038-89307 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 89314-89788 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 89808-91094 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 91099-92008 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 92017-93111 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 93162-93730 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 93746-94256 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 94257-95000 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 95018-96936 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 96964-97338 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 97342-97681 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 97684-99085 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Constituent Correspondence- 1998-2000 (mainly 2000)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 5044-37177 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 37642-61427 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 61570-83189 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 83284-96837 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 96858-98366 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 38428-98867 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 98878-99328 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 99334-100348 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 100406-101128 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 101132-101714 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 101733-102323 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 102393-102881 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 102955-104361 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 104369-105439 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 105477-106132 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 106150-106591 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 106628-107699 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 107713-108706 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 108721-109848 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 109849-110993 (Box 7, Folder 20)
- Constituent Correspondence- 2000
  - Correspondence Numbers, 111044-112719 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 112777-114174 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 114191-115348 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 115365-116178 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 200005-200768 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 200869-201171 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 201172-202083 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 202087-202621 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 202657-203193 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 203212-203793 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 203847-204072 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 204027-204587 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 204597-205111 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 205173-205738 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence Number, 205753 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 205840-2006433 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2006449-2006984 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2007072-2007848 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2007917-2008466 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2008474-2008743 (Box 8, Folder 20)
- Constituent Correspondence- 2000
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2008765-2009428 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2009441-2009849 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2009859-2010979 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2010981-2011808 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2011821-2012225 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2012227-2013905 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2013921-2014233 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2014268-2016570 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2016572-2022010 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2023833-2027077 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2027078-2027862 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2027863-2028680 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2028730-2030062 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2030072-2031905 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2031917-2033294 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2033309-2034852 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2034921-2037260 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2038290-2039517 (Box 9, Folder 18)
- Constituent Correspondence- 2000-2001
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2012240-2038308 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2038324-2039636 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2039657-2041146 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2041154-2042052 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2042055-2044185 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence Number, 2044291 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2044396-2047700 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2047712-2050398 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2050538-2051657 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2051665-2052821 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2052938-2054042 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2054086-2055952 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2056010-2057968 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2057983-2058427 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2058428-2059910 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2059939-2061594 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence Number, 2061693 (Box 10, Folder 17)
- Constituent Correspondence- 2001
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2061701-2062492 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2062531-2063200 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2063241-2064809 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2064813-2066111 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2066138-2067069 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2067077-2067871 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2067898-2068361 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2068372-2069127 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2069239-2069757 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2069763-2069898 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2069914-2070889 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2070895-2071296 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2071323-2071625 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence Number, 2071626 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2071720-2072013 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2072022-2072143 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2072143-2072259 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence Number, 2072261 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2072264-2072379 (Box 11, Folder 19)
- Constituent Correspondence- 2001
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2072414-2072464 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2072468-2072845 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2072848-2073162 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2073169-2073529 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2073537-2073877 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2073875-2073971 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2073973-2074352 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2074358-2074741 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2074743-2075189 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2075190-2075854 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2075918-2077763 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2077792-2098382 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2078414-2079202 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2079205-2080014 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2080021-2080928 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2080930-2081479 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2081483-2081861 (Box 12, Folder 17)
- Constituent Correspondence- 2001
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2081547-2082248 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2082257-2082727 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2082732-2083318 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2083326-2083570 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2083572-2082378 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2083877-2084295 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2084310-20874726 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2084742-2085353 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2085357-2085721 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence Number, 2085730 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2085765-2086634 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2086649-2087710 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2087489-2087630 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2087631-2088232 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2088279-2088862 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence Numbers, 2088863-2088866 (Box 13, Folder 16)
- Board Appointments
  - Appointments (Virginia Parole Board, Board for Virginia Forensic Science and Medical Institute, Criminal Justice Services) (Box 14, Folder 1)
- Correspondence- State Agencies
  - Commonwealth's Attorneys Services Council (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Department of Alcoholic Beverage Control (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Department of Correctional Education (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Department of Corrections (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Department of Criminal Justice Services (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Department of Emergency Services (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Department of Fire Programs (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Department of Juvenile Justice (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Department of Military Affairs (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Department of State Police (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Virginia Parole Board (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Memorandum to all Public Safety Agency Heads 1998 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Memorandum to all Public Safety Agency Heads 1999 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Memorandum to all Public Safety Agency Heads 2000 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Memorandum to all Public Safety Agency Heads 2001 (Box 14, Folder 16)
- Correspondence- Chronologial, 1998-2001
  - January-March 1998 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - April-June 1998 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - July-September 1998 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - October-December 1998 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - January-March 1999 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - April-June 1999 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - July-September 1999 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - October-December 1999 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - January-June 2000 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - July-December 2000 (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - January-December 2001 (Box 14, Folder 27)
- Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) & Department of Emergency Services
  - Hurrican Evacuation- Lane Reversal of I-64 (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - State of Emergency Declarations (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Terrorism-Correspondence, 1998-2001 (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - Terrorism-Virginia Preparedness and Security Panel, 28 September 2001 meeting (part 1 of 3) (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - Terrorism-Virginia Preparedness and Security Panel, 28 September 2001 meeting (part 2 of 3) (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - Terrorism-Virginia Preparedness and Security Panel, 28 September 2001 meeting (part 3 of 3) (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - Terrorism-Virginia Preparedness and Security Panel, Report to the Governor, 20 November 2001 (Box 14, Folder 35)
- Federal Grant Funding
  - Correspondence, 1998-2001 (Box 15, Folder 1)
- Legislative Initiatives
  - 1998-1999 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - 2000-2001 (Box 15, Folder 3)
- Special Programs
  - COPS (Community Oriented Policing Services) (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - 4 SAFE VA (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - ITT Night Vision (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - New Partnership Commission (part 1 of 2) (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - New Partnership Commission (part 2 of 2) (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Police Corps Program (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - SABRE Project (Substance Abuse Reduction Effort) (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Statewide Shared Land Mobile Radio System (part 1 of 2) (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Statewide Shared Land Mobile Radio System (part 2 of 2) (Box 15, Folder 12)